so many of you have been following the
work at cognitive policy works his last
few years because your supporters of
George Lake off and you're interested in
seeing framing put into use in the
political world so I thought today that
I would create this video to explain to
you a little bit about how the work in
framing has been developing and how it's
beginning to be implemented in the
political world through the perspective
I've had in the last few years doing
this kind of work so for those of you
who aren't familiar with framing I
recommend that you read don't think of
an elephant or thinking points by George
Lake off to start to get a flavor of
what it is but basically I'm going to
assume for the sake of brevity today
that you already understand what framing
is so basically in the last few years I
have been working with a number of
different organizations to implement
framing strategies in communications in
campaigns in organizational development
contexts and one of the challenges that
has made this slower than than you might
have thought initially is that framing
is about changing the conceptual models
that people have for understanding the
the way that people think about
different issues as well as how
organizations approach those issues and
that means since it's about conceptual
models it's about the ways that people
understand things and that goes much
deeper than language it goes deeper than
the word choices that are used in say a
press release or a political ad and get
all the way down to the level of the
relationships between different people
and ideas within organizations as well
as with the general public so over the
last several years there has been a
growing interest in the work of Lake off
you know george leigh coughs work on
political framing and there's been a
growing recognition among executive
level managers that is the people who
direct campaigns and her direct
communications they direct field
operations within unions for example to
implement framing strategies in there
and one of the big challenges has been
that in order to do framing work or to
communicate deeply at a level of values
in a way that resonates with people
there's a need to restructure the way
that organizations work and you know for
example in order to engage with the
public in a different way the field
operations staff at a union which is the
people that go out and organize people
on the ground has to collaborate
differently with the communications
department of the same Union and
possibly with communications departments
and unions of other compartment and of
field operations of other organizations
other unions other nonprofits other
political action committees and other
such groups so the collaboration element
has always been a challenge and getting
framing implemented well last week I
participated in something that I found
really exciting I was invited to the
United Kingdom into London to work with
a group of development ordered
organisations focusing on addressing
global poverty that have been grappling
with lay coughs work on framing for
about three years now in a really
serious focused way with the goal of
creating a coalition that brings all
those organizations together to address
the deep cultural obstacles to to having
the populace in the United Kingdom
collaborating to try to solve global
poverty and one of the cultural
obstacles is the suite of of
pro-consumer values that align with
self-interest and individualism and
selfish or materialistic drives and
those get in the way of trying to
promote more community-oriented socially
responsible values that are aligned with
the changes in global finance and with
market economies that perpetuate poverty
around the world so as we were coming
together to talk about the attempt to
bring framing into their work they
brought out a number of issues
institutional settings that make it
difficult for them to adopt framing and
that not that it stops them from doing
it but only that it goes more slowly and
that it's more challenging than then it
might at first seem and so it's really
exciting for me to see that the
directors of campaign departments and of
communications departments and a
fundraising departments within these
different development organizations are
coming together and having strategic
conversations about creating a joint
campaign to address mass consumerism in
the public at large so this is an
example of a group that is taking
framing very seriously and looking at
the deep structural challenges within
their own organizations and within their
own sector to try to address the
inherent contradictions that they've
found in the frames that they used in
the past and the frames that they will
need to move them closer to achieving
their mission which is to end poverty in
the world so you know this is a where on
the discussion is about much more than
language and it's getting deeply into
the experiences that people have within
the public at large around issues of
inequality and injustice issues around
economic fairness feelings people have
about corporations and corporate
governance and feelings about democracy
entrepreneurship and empowerment so
quite a gambit of deep issues that are
all part of the effort to address global
poverty and you know my role of course
was to bring an understanding of
cognitive science in the political mind
to the discussion but also to help shape
the understanding that the people in the
UK have about their place on the larger
global movement which is really miss
convergence that we're seeing across
issues to bring about a global
transformation whether it's social
justice or environmentalism or corporate
governance and globalization there is a
growing presence as we've seen in the
spring in the Occupy movement even a few
years ago we saw hence of it in the
Obama campaign and go back further to
the World Trade Organization protests in
Seattle in 1999 and on the the loss of
confidence that people had in the
election system here in the US after
2000 when I was found that Al Gore
actually won the popular vote but the
supreme court chose George Bush so in
this setting of people seeing that there
are bigger changes happening in the
world and recognizing that the attempts
that they've made in the past to address
the challenges have been too small too
limited or in some cases blind to the
unintended consequences that they have
that the work on framing has now gone
from talking about language which was
mainly about messaging and marketing to
a much deeper level of organizations
around the world and I personally work
now with them in the US Canada the
United Kingdom Germany Australia Spain
and a few other countries so I've been
kind of interacting internationally in
this discussion that they're now going
into this operational mode of bringing
framing into the very structure of
campaigns and therefore under the
structure of the organizations that run
those campaigns to learn how to do
things differently so this is a little
update for you that the framing work
that George Lakoff popularized a few
years ago is moving forward it's being
combined with other discoveries in
psychology and neuroscience anthropology
economics and other fields so you know
the social psychology research done by
Jonathan height on moral foundations and
political judgment that's being
incorporated and other other discoveries
like that as well so the work on framing
is moving forward it's just difficult to
do and there's progress in various
places around the world and and I'm an
exemplar of the fact that there's also
collaboration and open conversation
happening across these different groups
in different places around the world
as we really try to figure out how to
bring the insights from cognitive
science into an operational mode to
drive systemic pro-social cultural
change to address global problems so I
hope that you stay informed you know
that you keep following what we're doing
here at cognitive policy works and that
um you know contact us if there are ever
any ways that we might be able to work
together or rather we might be able to
be of assistance in the things that
you're working on so that's just a quick
update for you again I'm Joe Brewer the
founder and the director of cognitive
policy works and I'm really excited to
be part of this movement